Resume

ABHAY SARWADE

Phone: - 7887535829

Email: - sarwadea999@gmail.com

LinkedIn: - www.linkedin.com/in/abhay-sarwade-778324228

Address: - Prathmesh Apartment, Hinjewadi Phase 1, Pune-411057.

Objective: -

"To be an excellent professional and to be a part of an organization which provides constant learning of latest technological upgrades and provide career growth."

Professional summary: -

- Well versed with SDLC-Agile, Scrum methodologies
- Good understanding of the STLC process Test case documentation, review
- Experience on automation tool Selenium
- Involved in testing during the system testing or UAT phases
- Expertise in test management using JIRA
- Experience in working with the team to achieve project specific goals.
- Worked with TestNG framework.

Experience: -

Current Role: Software Analyst (Manual & Automation)

Designation: Software Tester

Experience: 1 Year 3 months in Software Testing QA

Roles and Responsibilities: -

- Performed requirement feasibility analysis for user stories and identified test scenarios/test objectives
- Contributed to the preparation of the defect management, communication and Test scope sections of the test plan
- Identified end-to-end test cases, regression suites and system test cases
- Involved in Test data identification and gathering
- Responsible for Smoke and Sanity test
- Participated in Daily scrum meetings
- Used JIRA for issue tracking
- Performed browser compatibility testing on browsers Chrome and Mozilla Firefox.
- Worked with the Development Team for understanding the details of Functional and Non-Functional Requirement on Web Online applications

Technical Skills: -

Key activities to be highlighted	 Automated Testing: Proficient in designing and implementing automated test scripts using Selenium. Understanding of API (Application Programming Interface) testing tools such as Postman, SOAP UI, or Rest Assured, and knowledge of concepts like RESTful APIs and JSON/XML can be valuable for testing web services and APIs. Analytical Skills: Strong analytical abilities to identify and address software issues efficiently. Address software issues efficiently.
Tools	Jira, whimsical, Figma, Click up, Eclipse.

Experience Summary: -

Organization	Interface11, Balaji Nagar, Pune				
Customer	Tata Technology				
Role	Software Analyst				
Period	05/01/2023 to 10/06/2023 - 5 Months				
Technologies	Selenium, Core java, Agile Methodology, MySQL, Manual Testing				
Responsibilities & Skills	 Performed requirement feasibility analysis for user stories and identified test scenarios/test objectives Contributed to the preparation of the defect management, communication and Test scope sections of the test plan Identified end-to-end test cases, regression suites and system test cases Involved in Test data identification and gathering Responsible for Smoke and Sanity test Participated in Daily scrum meetings Used JIRA for issue tracking Performed browser compatibility testing on browsers Chrome and Mozilla Firefox. Worked with the Development Team for understanding the details of Functional and Non-Functional Requirement on Web Online applications 				
Project Description	TCMS Application Planning for TCMS application, it is a comprehensive platform designed to assist students in managing and delivering educational content to student & developing comprehensive test cases that cover all aspects of the TCMS. including user registration, course management, content delivery. assessments, etc.				

Organization	Interface11, Balaji Nagar, Pune				
Role	Software Analyst				
Period	15/05/2023 to 20/11/2023 - 6 Months				
Technologies	Selenium, Core java, Agile Methodology, MySQL, Manual Testing				
Responsibilities & Skills	 Performed requirement feasibility analysis for user stories and identified test scenarios/test objectives Contributed to the preparation of the defect management, communication and Test scope sections of the test plan Identified end-to-end test cases, regression suites and system test cases Involved in Test data identification and gathering Responsible for Smoke and Sanity test Participated in Daily scrum meetings Used JIRA for issue tracking Performed browser compatibility testing on browsers Chrome and Mozilla Firefox. Worked with the Development Team for understanding the details of Functional and Non-Functional Requirement on Web Online applications 				
Project Description	FI Web Portal https://flaneroo.com/ Flaneroo is an immersive travel website designed to provide users with a personalized and unforgettable travel experience. The platform combines the charm of storytelling, convenient trip booking, luxurious villa accommodations, curated experiences, inspiring travel stories, and				

	L L C 44 D L "N D				
Organization	Interface11, Balaji Nagar, Pune				
Customer	Venkatesh Karad				
Role	Software Analyst				
Period	30/11/2023 to Present				
Technologies	Selenium, Core java, Agile Methodology, MySQL, Manual Testing				
Responsibilities & Skills	 Performed requirement feasibility analysis for user stories and identified test scenarios/test objectives Contributed to the preparation of the defect management, communication and Test scope sections of the test plan Identified end-to-end test cases, regression suites and system test cases Involved in Test data identification and gathering Responsible for Smoke and Sanity test Participated in Daily scrum meetings Used JIRA for issue tracking 				
Project Description	CRM project aims to establish a centralized system for managing customer interactions, sales leads, marketing campaigns, and customer service activities. The project will leverage CRM software to enhance communication, streamline processes, and improve the overall customer experience.				

Additional Details: -

- Good at analysis front and finding technical issues.
- Good Mutual communication within the team and better at managing interpersonal issues.
- Good at taking Decisions at a critical situation after overall analysis for the issue.

Education Summary: -

Qualification	Percentage/Grade
Bachelor of Engineering	7.74 CGPA
Diploma	67%
SSC	65.20%

D	ore	on	al	De	tail	lc٠	

Date of Birth: - 31/03/2000

Father Name: - Abhay V. Sarwade

Gender: - Male

Marital Status: - Unmarried

Nationality: - Indian

Declaration: -

I he	ereby decl	are that all	the inform	ation pro	vided abo	ove is cur	rent and	best to my	/ knowledge	e and belief.

Date: -

Signature

Abhay Sarwade